Guide to the North Carolina Council of Churches records, 1935-2019 RL.00934
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Accession (2001-0135)
  - Press Clippings (Box 33)
    - Migrant Ministry, 1978, 1983, 1984 (Box 33)
    - Miscellaneous, 1976, 1878, 1979, 1983 (Box 33)
    - N.C. Council of Churches, 1977, 1979 (Box 33)
    - Nuclear Weapons Freeze, 1981-1983 (Box 33)
    - Refugees, 1979 (Box 33)
    - Tax Reform, 1974, 1975, 1977 (Box 33)
    - Tobacco, 1982-1984 (Box 33)
    - Union and J.P. Stevens, 1977 (Box 33)
    - USA/USSR, 1984 (Box 33)
  - Misc. Correspondence, V-W, 1976, 2 folders (Box 33)
  - Wiley Correspondence, 1976 (Box 33)
  - Union/J.P. Stevens - Misc. Correspondence, 1976 (Box 33)
  - Union, 1976, 6 folder (Box 33)
  - Misc. Correspondence, T, 1976 (Box 33)
  - Social Action Boards, 1976 (Box 33)
  - Summer Camps, 1976 (Box 33)
  - Misc. Correspondence, C, 1976 (Box 33)
  - Calendar, 1976 (Box 33)
  - Congress - Misc., 1976 (Box 33)
  - Church Council Bulletin, 1976 (Box 33)
  - Misc. Correspondence, R, 1976 (Box 33)
  - Resolutions Consented To, 39th Annual Assembly, 1976 (Box 33)
  - Misc. Correspondence, S, 1976 (Box 33)
  - Shriver Consultation, 1976 (Box 33)
  - Misc. Correspondence, B, 1976 (Box 33)
  - 39th Annual Assembly, 1976 (Box 33)
  - Correspondence, 1976, 12 folders (Box 33)
  - Health Insurance, 1985 (Box 33)
  - Photos of Leaders, 1984 (Box 33)
  - Russian Visit to U.S., 1984 (Box 33)
  - Tobacco, 1984, 2 folders (Box 33)
  - Shand Report, 1984 (Box 33)
  - Tobacco, 1985 (Box 33)
  - Advisory Committee on Religious Ministry in Prison, 1974 (Box 33)
  - Greensboro Massacre, 1985 (Box 33)
  - Day Care, 1983 (Box 33)
  - Child Advocacy, 1983 (Box 33)
  - Central America, 1985 (Box 33)
  - Africa Emergency Committee, 1986 (Box 33)
  - National Council of Churches, Letters, 1985, 5 folders (Box 33)
  - Finance, 1980-1986, 2 folders (Box 34)
  - Drunk Driving, 1986, 4 folders (Box 34)
  - Week of Prayer, 1984-1985, 3 folders (Box 34)
  - Anniversary, 1985, 7 folders (Box 34)
  - Christian Unity, 1980-1986 (Box 34)
  - Logo Designs (Box 34)
  - Peace Committee, 1983-1985, 3 folders (Box 34)
  - Appointments, 1984 (Box 34)
  - Misc. Correspondence, A-Z, 1984 (Box 34)
  - Correspondence, 1984, 12 folders (Box 34)
  - Committee Meetings, 1984
    - Administrative (Box 34)
    - Christian Education, 3 folders (Box 34)
    - Christian Social Ministries, 4 folders (Box 34)
    - Christian Unity, 6 folders (Box 34)
    - Communications, 4 folders (Box 34)
    - Youth Ministry (Box 34)
    - Criminal Justice, 11 folders (Box 34)
    - Equal Rights, 9 folders (Box 34)
  - Committee Meetings, 1984 (Box 35)
    - Local Ecumenical Ministries, 2 folders (Box 35)
    - Executive Board, 2 folders (Box 35)
    - Economic Justice, 2 folders (Box 35)
    - Migrant Ministry, 21 folders (Box 35)
    - Security and Peace, 12 folders (Box 35)
    - Tobacco, 8 folders (Box 35)
  - Raleigh Report Costs, 1987 (Box 35)
  - Ecumenical Conf. on Peace-Making, 1986 (Box 35)
  - Conscientious Objection Seminar, 1986 (Box 35)
  - Baptism, Eucharist, and Ministry, 1985 (Box 35)
  - 50th Anniversary Convention, 1985, 2 folders (Box 35)
  - Committees, 1987
    - Christian Nurture (Box 35)
    - Christian Education, 3 folders (Box 35)
    - Christian Social Ministry (Box 35)
    - Christian Unity, 5 folders (Box 35)
    - Church and Public Education, 5 folders (Box 35)
    - Communications, 2 folders (Box 35)
    - Criminal Justice, 5 folders (Box 35)
    - Equal Rights, 10 folders (Box 35)
    - Executive Board (Box 35)
    - Administrative, 2 folders (Box 35)
    - Finance Committee (Box 35)
    - Migrant Ministry, 8 folders (Box 35)
    - Rural/Farm Crisis, 2 folders (Box 35)
    - Peace and Security, 7 folders (Box 35)
    - Racial Justice (Box 35)
  - Racial Justice Committee, 1987, 3 folders (Box 36)
  - Appointments, 1991 (Box 36)
  - Committee Meetings, 1991
    - Aids Task Force, 3 folders (Box 36)
    - Christian Unity, 3 folders (Box 36)
    - Communications (Box 36)
    - Criminal Justice, 19 folders (Box 36)
    - Equal Rights, 6 folders (Box 36)
    - Executive, 2 folders (Box 36)
    - Administrative (Box 36)
    - Farmworker Ministry, 8 folders (Box 36)
    - Public Relations (Box 36)
  - Church Council Bulletin, 1949-2001, 36 folders (Box 36)
  - Ruth B. Minter, 1983 (Box 36)
  - North Carolinians for Effective Citizenship, 1983 (Box 36)
  - Tobacco Study and Hearings, 1983, 2 folders (Box 36)
  - House of Delegates, 1983, 5 folders (Box 36)
  - Hunger Committee, 1980 (Box 36)
  - Office/Subject Files, J-L, 1981-1983 (Box 36)
  - Office/Subject Files, L-S, 1980-1983, 80 folders (Box 37)
    Includes Migrant Ministry Committee and Migrant Housing, 1981-1983; Nuclear Freeze Resolution, 1983; the Raleigh Report, 1983; Refugee Resettlement Committee, 1981-1983; Peace and Security Committee, 1982-1983; and Tobacco Study Task Force, 1983.
  - Letters, 1974 (Box 37)
  - Raleigh Report, 1987, 5 folders (Box 38)
  - CK's summary of NCCC activities, 1987 (Box 38)
  - Telephone message log, 1986-1987 (Box 38)
  - Subject/Office Files, F-Z 1982, 57 folders (Box 38)
    Includes House of Delegates material, 1981-1982; Migrant Ministry Committee, 1982; and Security and Peace Committee, 1982.
  - Hunger materials and [loose materials], 1974, 2 folders (Box 38)
  - Finance materials, quarterly statements, and appeal letters, 1983-1984, 8 folders (Box 38)
  - Financial materials, ca. 1972-1983, 2 folders (Box 39)
  - Minutes, Executive Board meetings, 1967-1973, 2 folders (Box 39)
  - Office/Subject Files, 1972, 32 folders (Box 39)
    Includes newspaper clippings; budget information; and welfare information
  - Incoming letters to Collins Kilburn, 1972-1973, 3 folders (Box 39)
  - Office/Subject Files, 1988, 5 folders (Box 39)
  - Caring Program for Children, 1992 (Box 39)
  - Caring Program for Children, 1989-1993, 21 folders (Box 40)
  - Incoming letters to Collins Kilburn, 1988, 5 folders (Box 40)
  - Press Clippings (Box 40)
  - Land Sale, 1978 (Box 40)
  - Death Penalty, 1978-1979 (Box 40)
  - [J.P.] Stevens Paper, 1976-1977 (Box 40)
  - NCCC Resolutions and Statements, 1980 (Box 40)
  - Commission on Social Ministries, Nuclear Energy Panel, 1980 (Box 40)
  - NCCC Restructuring, 1969, [1979], 2 folders (Box 40)
  - [Kilburn] Profile, 1981 (Box 40)
  - Wilmington 10 (Box 40)
  - Wiley, Samuel S. Retirement (Box 40)
  - Child Abuse Task Force, 1979, 2 folders (Box 40)
  - Criminal Justice and Death Penalty, 2 folders (Box 40)
  - ERA, 1978-1979, 2 folders (Box 40)
  - Fraud and Abuse in the Food Stamp Program, 1982, 2 folders (Box 40)
  - Presumptive Sentencing (Box 40)
  - World Council Assembly, 1983, 2 folders (Box 40)
  - Family (Box 40)
  - Chaplains-Military (Box 40)
  - Office/Subject Files, E-Z, 1980-1983, 59 folders (Box 41)
    Includes Labor-Management Committee, 1979-1981; Migrant Ministry, 1980; Public Relations Committee, 1979-1980; and Refugee Resettlement Committee, 1980
  - Outgoing mail log, 1984-1986 (Box 41)
  - Office/Subject Files, A-F and P-R, 1989, 59 folders (Box 41)
    Includes AIDS Task Force; Criminal Justice Committee; Equal Rights Committee; Farmworker Ministry Committee; and Peace and Security Committee.
  - Conference on Racism, Poverty, and Economic Justice, 1989, 7 folders (Box 42)
  - Prison Reform, 1972, 9 folders (Box 42)
  - Drug Abuse, 1972 (Box 42)
  - Ecumenical Witness, 1972 (Box 42)
  - Executive Board, NCCC, 1972 (Box 42)
  - Experimental Ministry, 1972 (Box 42)
  - General Assembly Task Group, 1973 (Box 42)
  - Lutheran Church, 1972 (Box 42)
  - Legal Aid, 1972 (Box 42)
  - News Releases, 1972 (Box 42)
  - Migrant Correspondence, 1972 (Box 42)
  - Newsletter, Southern Conference, United Church of Christ, 1970-1972 (Box 42)
  - Migrant Ministry (Box 42)
  - Out-of-State Council of Churches (Box 42)
  - Offender Aid and Restoration, 1972 (Box 42)
  - Rental Office Space (Box 42)
  - Peace Action Network (Box 42)
  - Ben Chavis (Box 42)
  - Child Care (Box 42)
  - Civil Liberties (Box 42)
  - Seminar on Church and Community, 1971, 4 folders (Box 42)
  - The Churchman, 1971 (Box 42)
  - Church Women United. (Box 42)
  - Misc. Files, C, 1972 (Box 42)
  - Church Council Bulletin, 1969-1972 (Box 42)
  - Church and Labor Task Group, 1971, 2 folders (Box 42)
  - Commission on Christian Ministries, 1971 (Box 42)
  - Budget, 1971 (Box 42)
  - Social Ministries Report, 1972 (Box 42)
  - Misc. Correspondence, 1971 (Box 42)
  - Council of Churches Social Ministries, Membership, 1972 (Box 42)
  - Communications Network, 1968-1972 (Box 42)
  - Misc. Correspondence, 1972 (Box 42)
  - Annual Assembly, 1970-1972 (Box 42)
  - Calendar, 1972 (Box 42)
  - Misc. Files, B, 1972 (Box 42)
  - Presbyterians, 1972 (Box 42)
  - CCSM, 1976, 6 folders (Box 42)
  - North Carolina Consumers Council, 1976 (Box 42)
  - Committee on Government and Legislation, 1976 (Box 42)
  - Criminal Justice Committee, 1976 (Box 42)
  - Misc. Correspondence, D, 1976 (Box 42)
  - Director of Social Ministries, Annual Report, 1976 (Box 42)
  - District Legislative Action Representatives, 1976 (Box 42)
  - Death Penalty, 1976 (Box 42)
  - Misc. Correspondence, E, 1976 (Box 43)
  - Ecumenical Groups, Local and Statewide, 1976 (Box 43)
  - ERA, 1976, 4 folders (Box 43)
  - Misc. Correspondence, F-H, 1976, 3 folders (Box 43)
  - Gun Control, 1976 (Box 43)
  - Hunger, Welfare, and Economic Justice Task Group, 1976, 4 folders (Box 43)
  - Collins Kilburn, Letters, 1990, 5 folders (Box 43)
  - Correspondence, 1989, 12 folders (Box 43)
  - Appointments, 1989 (Box 43)
  - Caring Program for Children, 1989 (Box 43)
  - Computer, Request to IBM Application, 1989 (Box 43)
  - Church Council Bulletin, 1989 Apr.-July, 2 folders (Box 43)
  - Outgoing Mail Log, 1987 Jan. 1 - 1989 July 25 (Box 43)
  - Church Council Bulletin, 1989 (Box 43)
  - House of Delegates, 1989, 4 folders (Box 43)
  - Judicatory Heads, 1989, 2 folders (Box 43)
  - Bishops Lunch, 1989 (Box 43)
  - Legislative Seminars, 1989 (Box 43)
  - Press Releases, 1989, 2 folders (Box 43)
  - N.C. General Assembly Session, 1989 (Box 43)
  - Raleigh Report, 1989, 8 folders (Box 43)
  - Slide-Talk Show, 1989 (Box 43)
  - Down South NCCC-USSR Travel Seminar Reunion, 1989 (Box 43)
  - Misc. Correspondence, 1989 (Box 43)
  - Telephone Message Log, 1988 Apr. 20 - 1989 June 5 (Box 44)
  - UM Hymnal and Songfest, 1989 (Box 44)
  - Homer Bass, CPA, 1994 (Box 44)
  - Legislative Planning committee, 1994 (Box 44)
  - Personnel, Application Forms (Box 44)
  - Computer, 1990 (Box 44)
  - Church Council Bulletin, 1993 (Box 44)
  - Criminal Justice, 1993 (Box 44)
  - Executive Board, 1993 (Box 44)
  - Farmworker Ministry Committee, 1993 (Box 44)
  - Miscellaneous, 1993 (Box 44)
  - Peace Committee, 1993 (Box 44)
  - Jeanne Audruy Powers, What Does it Mean to Belong to an Ecumenical Organization?, 1994 (Box 44)
  - Personnel, Time Sheets, 1994 (Box 44)
  - Correspondence, 1994, 18 folders (Box 44)
  - New ERA File, 1979 Mar. 23, 4 folders (Box 44)
  - ERA, 1980, 4 folders (Box 45)
  - Outgoing Mail Log, 1992 Mar. 2 - 1995 July 25 (Box 45)
  - Local Emergency Assistance Providers (Box 45)
  - ENACT Conference, 1994 (Box 45)
  - Women, Faith, and Violence, 1993 (Box 45)
  - Bishop's Lunch, 1994 (Box 45)
  - N.C. General Assembly, 1994 (Box 45)
  - N.C. Council of Churches, Summary of Activities, 1994 (Box 45)
  - National Association of Ecumenical Staff, 1994 (Box 45)
  - Media P.R. 1994, 2 folders (Box 45)
  - Nominating Committee, 1994 (Box 45)
  - House of Delegates, 1994, 5 folders (Box 45)
  - Fax, Outgoing, 1994, 2 folders (Box 45)
  - Children's Sabbath, 1994 (Box 45)
  - Miscellaneous, A-Z, 1995 (Box 45)
  - Legislative Seminar, 1993, 11 folders (Box 45)
  - Previous Years Miscellaneous Files (Box 45)
  - Chaplains (N.C.), 1991 (Box 45)
  - Development/Fund Rasing Committee, 1992 (Box 45)
  - Legislative Seminar, 1991, 5 folders (Box 45)
  - Peace Committee, 1992, 2 folders (Box 45)
  - Criminal Justice Committee, 1990, 3 folders (Box 45)
  - Commission on Religion in Appalachia, 1989 (Box 45)
  - Raleigh Report, 1983 (Box 45)
  - Workshop on Jewish-Christian Relations, 1989 (Box 45)
  - ElderCare, 1993 (Box 45)
  - Children and Families Advocacy Committee, 1994 (Box 45)
  - Christian Unity Committee, 1994 (Box 45)
  - Criminal Justice Committee, 1994 (Box 45)
  - Equal Rights Committee, 1994 (Box 45)
  - Executive Board, 1994 (Box 45)
  - Executive Board, 1994, 3 folders (Box 46)
  - Business and Finance Committee, 1994 (Box 46)
  - Racial Justice Committee, 1994 (Box 46)
  - Farmworker Ministry, 1994, 2 folders (Box 46)
  - Legislative Program Committee, 1994 (Box 46)
  - House of Delegates, 1994, 2 folders (Box 46)
  - Institutional Racism Conference, 1994 (Box 46)
  - Church Council Bulletin, 1994 (Box 46)
  - Refugee Resettlement Program, 1994 (Box 46)
  - Photo Albums and Scrapbooks (Box 46)
  - NC Council of Churches, Annual Meeting Reports, 1968-1975, 4 folders (Box 46)
  - Annual Meetings, 1955-1964 (Box 46)
  - Executive Board Meetings, 1985-1990, 4 folders (Box 46)
  - Communications Committee, 1979-1988, 2 folders (Box 46)
  - Executive Board Meeting Minutes, 1979-1984, 6 folders (Box 46)
  - NCCC/MEW Delegation, 1991 (Box 46)
  - Press Release, 1991 (Box 46)
  - Bishops and Judicatory Executive Luncheon, 1991, 3 folders (Box 46)
  - House of Delegates, Nominating Committee, 1991 (Box 46)
  - Judicatory Heads Letter to Governor Regarding October Executions, 1991 (Box 46)
  - Raymon Hunt, President NCCC, 1991 (Box 46)
  - Communications Committee, Upcoming Meeting, 1989 (Box 46)
  - Personnel Committee, 1991-1992, 2 folders (Box 46)
  - Legislative Study Committee, 1991 (Box 46)
  - Rural Crisis Committee, 1991 (Box 46)
  - Interfaith Disaster Committee, 1991 (Box 46)
  - Correspondence, 1991 Jan.-Feb., 2 folders (Box 46)
  - Correspondence, 1992, 15 folders (Box 47)
  - Church Council Bulletin, 1992 July (Box 47)
  - Focus on Farmworkers in North Carolina, 1992, 4 folders (Box 47)
  - General Files, A-Z, 1992 (Box 47)
  - Appointments, 1992 (Box 47)
  - Church Council Bulletin, 1992, 3 folders (Box 47)
  - House of Delegates, 1992, 2 folders (Box 47)
  - House of Delegates, Membership, 1992 (Box 47)
  - House of Delegates, 1992, 4 folders (Box 47)
  - Nominating Committee, 1992 (Box 47)
  - Distinguished Service Award, 1992 (Box 47)
  - Judicatory Heads, 1992 (Box 47)
  - Press Releases, 1992 (Box 47)
  - North Carolina General Assembly, 1992 (Box 47)
  - People for the American Way (Box 47)
  - Execution Alert, 1992 Oct. 1 (Box 47)
  - Raleigh Report, 1990-1991, 4 folders (Box 47)
  - Telephone Message Log, 1991 Sept. 19 - 1992 Apr. 29, 2 folders (Box 47)
  - Letters to U.S. Congressmen, 1991-1992 (Box 48)
  - Letter to President George H W Bush, 1991 Jan. 11 (Box 48)
  - Vision Interfaith Satellite Network, 1992 (Box 48)
  - Committee Meetings, 1992
    - Child and Family Advocacy, 6 folders (Box 48)
    - Christian Unity, 5 folders (Box 48)
    - Communications (Box 48)
    - Criminal Justice, 14 folders (Box 48)
    - Equal Rights, 6 folders (Box 48)
    - Executive Board, 5 folders (Box 48)
    - Administrative, 3 folders (Box 48)
    - Farmworker Ministry, 12 folders (Box 48)
    - Business and Finance (Box 48)
    - Health Care Justice, 8 folders (Box 48)
    - Legislative Program, 2 folders (Box 48)
    - Local Ecumenical Ministries, 2 folders (Box 48)
    - Interfaith Disaster, 2 folders (Box 48)
    - Racial Justice, 2 folders (Box 48)
    - Rural Crisis (Box 48)
    - Peace and Security, 10 folders (Box 48)
  - Raleigh Report, 1991 Apr. 18 (Box 48)
  - Correspondence, 1991 July-Dec., 7 folders (Box 48)
  - Alternatives to Military Service (Box 49)
  - Committee Files, 1995
    - Personnel (Box 49)
    - Racism, 2 folders (Box 49)
    - Finance (Box 49)
    - Child and Family Advocacy, 4 folders (Box 49)
    - Christian Unity, 4 folders (Box 49)
    - Criminal Justice, 11 folders (Box 49)
    - Equal Rights, 8 folders (Box 49)
    - Executive Board, 6 folders (Box 49)
    - Administrative, 3 folders (Box 49)
    - Farmworker Ministry, 13 folders (Box 49)
    - Personnel, 3 folders (Box 49)
    - Racial Justice, 6 folders (Box 49)
  - IRS (Box 49)
  - Grant Applications, 1993, 24 folders (Box 49)
  - Financial Reports, 1993, 12 folders (Box 49)
  - Correspondence, 1991 Jan. - June, 8 folders (Box 50)
  - Church Council Bulletin, 1991, 3 folders (Box 50)
  - House of Delegates, 1991, 6 folders (Box 50)
  - Lex Mathews Land Stewardship Conference, 1988 (Box 50)
  - NC Council of Churches, Brief Description of Current Program (Box 50)
  - N.C. General Assembly, 1991 (Box 50)
  - N.C. Low Income Housing Coalition (Box 50)
  - Resume, Collins Kilburn, 1977 (Box 50)
  - Sanctuary (Box 50)
  - Refugee Resettlement, Ongoing Minutes, 1982-1984 (Box 50)
  - Consultation on the Crisis in Robeson County, 1989 (Box 50)
  - N.C. Council of Churches, Annual Report, 1984-1985 (Box 50)
  - U.S. Congress Directories, 1967-1983 (Box 50)
  - Committee Meetings, 1991
    - Finance, 3 folders (Box 50)
    - Executive Board, 5 folders (Box 50)
    - Social Ministries, 2 folders (Box 50)
    - Legislative Program, 2 folders (Box 50)
    - Ecumenical Social Services (Box 50)
    - Interfaith Disaster Response, 2 folders (Box 50)
    - Peace and Security, 9 folders (Box 50)
  - Workplace Reform Mission, 1995 (Box 51)
  - Caring Program for Children, 1996, 14 folders (Box 51)
  - Letters, 1975, 5 folders (Box 51)
  - Letters, 1976 Jan.-July, 2 folders (Box 51)
  - Annual Meeting, Report of Activities, 1957-1969, 3 folders (Box 51)
  - Letters, 1972, 5 folders (Box 51)
  - Legislative Programs, Other Councils and Groups, 1971 (Box 51)
  - Legislative Program, 1970-1971, 4 folders (Box 51)
  - Legislative Seminar, 1974, 2 folders (Box 51)
  - Prison Stuff, 1973, 2 folders (Box 51)
  - Penal Reform, 1972 (Box 51)
  - Poverty-Welfare (Box 51)
  - Finance, 1972, 3 folders (Box 51)
  - Finance, 1971 (Box 52)
  - Caledonia Thing, 1972 (Box 52)
  - Prison Seminar, 1972 (Box 52)
  - Report on the Planning Consultation for Commission and Committee Chairmen, 1969, 2 folders (Box 52)
  - Landlord-Tenant Laws, 1973, 2 folders (Box 52)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1973, 6 folders (Box 52)
  - Juvenile Corrections (Box 52)
  - Welfare (Box 52)
  - Finance, 1974 (Box 52)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1973, 2 folders (Box 52)
  - Title XX Stuff (Box 52)
  - Commission on Christian Social Ministries Meeting, 1973 (Box 52)
  - Church and Community Seminar, 1971 (Box 52)
  - Seminar on Church and Community, 1972 (Box 52)
  - Gaventa, Bill, 1975 (Box 52)
  - Tax Reform Stuff, 1973-1974, 3 folders (Box 52)
  - Wake Advancement Center (Box 52)
  - Day Care, 1976 (Box 52)
  - Prison Seminar, 1973 Oct. (Box 52)
  - Peace Booth, 1973 (Box 52)
  - Collins Kilburn, Graduate School notes and papers, 1973, 8 folders (Box 52)
  - Project Equality (Box 52)
  - Collins Kilburn, Graduate School Notes, 1973, 5 folders (Box 52)
  - Legal sized materials removed from earlier boxes (Box 53)
    - December, 1977 [from box 15] (Box 53)
    - Criminal Justice Committee, Presumptive Sentencing Bill, 1979 [removed from box 6] (Box 53)
    - Peace, 1964-1970, 3 folders (Box 53)
    - Legal size material from box 4 (Box 53)
    - Conference on Racism, Poverty, and Economic Justice, 1989 [removed from box 42] (Box 53)
  - Migrant Ministry, 1958-1991, 9 folders (Box 53)
    Includes color and black-and-white photographs and a scrapbook from which photos have been removed and refoldered. [Scrapbook moved to oversize folder].
  - Photo albums and scrapbooks from box 46, 1981-1989, 4 albums in 21 folders (Box 54)
    Includes color and black-and-white prints and color and black-and-white negatives.
  - Migrant Ministry scrapbook (in "Pony Tail Photo Scrapbook") from box 53 (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Migrant Ministry publicity, including black and white photographs and negatives (Oversize-folder 2)
- Unnumbered accession, 1 boxes
  Addition (dated 1971-1975 and undated) contains materials related to the organization's ministry with the aging. There are brochures, fliers, publications, and manuals, many regarding how to establish a meals-on-wheels program.
  - Brochures, fliers, publications, and manuals (Box 1)
- Accession (2007-0133), 11 boxes
  The addition (5,000 items, 6.6 lin. ft.; dated 1966-1982) contains operational and subject files including correspondence, executive board meeting files, minutes, reports from sub-committees, and files related to similar religious organizations.
  - Conference files, annual reports, and budget reports, 1972-1978 (Box 1)
  - Conference files, annual reports, and budget reports, 1973-1977 (Box 2)
  - Church Women United in NC files, 1968-1974 (Box 3)
  - Commission on Christian Nurture files, 1974-1976 (Box 3)
  - Commission on Christian Social Ministries files, 1972 (Box 3)
  - Committee on Church and Community files (Box 4)
  - Director of Social Ministries files (Box 4)
  - Subject files
    - American Revolution bicentennial (Box 4)
    - Bible-reading workshop (Box 4)
    - Biographies (Box 4)
    - Black Churchmen's Movement (Box 4)
    - Blind (Box 4)
    - Mrs. Helen W. Brockwell (Box 4)
    - Calendars (Box 4)
    - Composite calendar (Box 4)
    - Career and personal counseling service (Box 4)
    - Central prison (Box 4)
    - Chestnut Ridge, May 6-7, 1978 (Box 4)
    - Children's work (Box 4)
    - Christian Action League (Box 4)
    - Christian Education Commission (Box 4)
    - Christmas (Box 4)
    - Church Executive Development Board (Box 4)
    - Clemency Information Center (Box 4)
    - Commission for Human Skills and Resource Development (Box 4)
    - Creative Ministry Support Club (Box 4)
    - Christian Social Ministry (Box 4)
    - Church & Industry Institute (Box 4)
    - Civil Defense Agency (Box 5)
    - Community Development (Box 5)
    - Complex, Inc. (Box 5)
    - Continuing education (Box 5)
    - Council Organization and Extension (Box 5)
    - Development (Box 5)
    - Division of church and society (Box 5)
    - Ecumenical Continuing Education Center at Yale (Box 5)
    - Emergency Ministry for Veteran Services (Box 5)
    - Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (Box 5)
    - Evaluation Committee (Box 5)
    - Committee on Evangelism, 1968 (Box 5)
    - Evangelism Winston-Salem (Box 5)
    - Workshop on Evangelism - Registration (Box 5)
    - Extremism (Box 5)
    - Good Neighbor Council (Box 5)
    - Handicapped (Box 5)
    - Marie Hill (Box 5)
    - Samuel S. Hill, Jr. (Box 5)
    - Raymond A. Horn (Box 5)
    - Housing (Box 5)
    - Human Relations (Box 5)
    - Hyde County (Box 5)
    - Inter-church Co-operation (Box 5)
    - Interreligious Foundation for Community Organization (Box 6)
    - Indian affairs (Box 6)
    - Instrotech (Box 6)
    - Interpreters' House (Box 6)
    - Israel (Box 6)
    - JACS (Box 6)
    - Japan International Christian University Foundation, Inc. (Box 6)
    - Jewish community (Box 6)
    - National Conference of Christians & Jews (Box 6)
    - Joint Ministries (Box 6)
    - Joint Strategy and Action Committee (Box 6)
    - Juvenile Correction (Box 6)
    - Key 73 (Box 6)
    - Martin Luther King, Jr. (Box 6)
    - Lamar Society (Box 7)
    - Laymen (Box 7)
    - Leadership Development and Support System for Church Education in Appalachia (Box 7)
    - Legislature and public morals (Box 7)
    - Long-range planning (Box 7)
    - Long-range planning consultation, 1968 (Box 7)
    - Long-range planning consultation for denominational leaders-registration (Box 7)
    - Long-range planning consultation, February 26-27, 1968 (Box 7)
    - Lumbee Indians (Box 7)
    - Prison reform (Box 8)
    - Project equality (Box 8)
    - Requests for information (Box 8)
    - David & Andrea Weddington (Box 8)
    - Youth for Global Awareness (Box 8)